Vishnu Ajith

Infrastructure Engineer





devops.ajithv@gmail.com

To contribute to a solution oriented, team environment. Maximize interpersonal and organizational skills and knowledge. Engage in opportunities to utilize experience and motivation, including learning new technologies, to provide professional growth for both the company, and myself



Work Experience Summary

- A competent professional with 2.8 years of experience in Red Hat Enterprise Linux Administration and Critical Incident Management.
- Provided L2 & L3 level of support for RedHat Enterprise Linux environment.
- Worked on VMWare ESXi based environment.
- Have knowledge in handling the physical servers such as CISCO & Dell AtoS.
- Experience in handling the Cloud environment (Azure & AWS).
- Worked on Satellite, Cloud and Manual patching.
- Worked on package management using RPM and YUM.
- Worked on provisioning the file permissions and also handled user and group management.
- Worked on configuring file systems using LVM and also managed SWAP FS.
- Worked on deploying VM's using template.
- Have knowledge on cloning Virtual machines.
- Worked on handling customized SUDO privileges.
- Have good troubleshooting knowledge on NFS and Network related issues.
- Have good knowledge in handling the storage performance issue, process issue and memory issue.
- Have L2 knowledge on the VMWare end.
- Have experience in handling the server monitoring tool Nagios.
- Experience in recovering the servers from MM mode.
- Handled filesystem corruption issues which includes the xfs and fsck repairs.
- Handled most of the critical Infrastructure changes associated with the Linux environment.
- Worked on automation using Python, Shell scripting and Ansible.
- Experience in Enterprise incident management, Infrastructure change co-ordination,

- Disaster recovery change co-ordination, Auditing and Client engagement.
- Have knowledge in various development, testing and deployment tools such as Git, Jenkins, Docker, Nagios, Kubernetes & Ansible.
- Have knowledge in developing Continuous Integration/ Delivery pipelines.



Project Experience

2022-01 - Current

Tech Lead - Linux (Caterpillar Inc)

Infosys Itd, Bangalore

- Working as a Team Lead for Linux & Unix track End to end management of the whole track which consist of 12 members.
- Being major part of hosting services division by maintaining and managing 5000+ RHEL servers (Non-Prod and Prod).
- Have good experience in working on all server management related activities which include identifying hardware and software solutions, troubleshooting technical issues, diagnosing and expediting faults related to OS.
- Experience in working on critical and high priority tickets and also directly dealing on technical escalations.
- Have relevant experience in working on all critical changes done to infrastructure end (Linux).
- Experience in handling Satellite, Manual and Cloud patching.
- Experience in handling migration activity from on prem to Cloud.
- Have good knowledge in handling IT Compliance SOX audit.
- Handled various tech meetings with client and other senior level management.
- Automated manual tasks using shell scripting in Linux environment.
- Resolved problems, improved operations and provided exceptional service.
- Exhibit exceptional leadership qualities.

2021-01 - 2021-12

Critical Incident Manager & Automation Developer Infosys Ltd, Bangalore

- Experience in Enterprise incident management, Infrastructure change co-ordination, Disaster recovery change co-ordination, Auditing and Client engagement.
- Worked with automation team to bring extensive impacts on cost reduction and effort reduction part pertaining to all critical tracks in service delivery domain.
- Modified python scripts used for reporting activities at management level

2020-08 - 2020-12

Operation Executive Trainee

Infosys Ltd., Mysore

- Completed training in Python, MySQL, MongoDB, Mainframe (COBOL, JCL), ITSM and Middleware (Tomcat, IIS)
- Exhibited excellent technical, communication and leadership skills.

Education

2015-06 - 2017-05

Bachelor of Computer Applications

St. Joseph's College, Devagiri (Autonomous) - Devagiri, Calicut

• Completed Bachelor's in Computer Application with 69.8%.

ISC 2: Computer Science

Auxilium Nava Jyoti ICSE School - Kunnamangalam, Calicut

- Secured 79.8% in the ISC board exams.
- Topped in Computer Science by securing 100%.



Skills

- Programming Languages Python, Java, C++, JavaScript, HTML, CSS,
 Bootstrap, Tailwind, React JS & Django
- Automation/DevOps/Build tool Shell Scripting, Ansible, Docker, Git, Jenkins
 & GitHub
- Cloud Azure & AWS
- OS platform Linux, Unix and Windows
- Monitoring stack Nagios
- Ticketing Tool ServiceNow
- Virtualization Tool VMWare & Virtual Box
- Mainframe COBOL & JCL
- Middleware Tomcat & IIS
- DB SQL, MongoDB
- Data Analytics Power BI & Tableau
- Creative thinking and problem solving
- Hosting Tool Firebase



Certifications

- AZ 900 Certified in Azure Fundamentals (Microsoft)
- Certified in Advanced Core Python Code Challenges (LinkedIn)
- Certified in RedHat on Azure (Infosys)
- Certified in RedHat Engineer (Infosys)
- Certified in Python 101 for Data Science (IBM)
- Certified in Google Analytics (Google)



Honors & Awards

Caterpillar - Infosys Services Award (Feb 2023)

 Received the award from the CIO of Caterpillar Inc for the exemplary performance as an Infrastructure engineer in the hosting services division.

Caterpillar - Support & Projects Award (Oct 2022)

 Received the award from the Divisional Manager of Caterpillar Inc for the exemplary contribution to Caterpillar support and projects in the hosting services division, specially recognized for the efforts in streamlining the Linux track.

Infosys Rising Star Award (Sept 2022)

• Received the award from the Group Project Manager for the efficient handle of Linux track in SD domain.

Infosys Rise Insta Award (Aug 2022)

 Awarded for exhibiting the technical excellence in Service Delivery domain (Linux).

Infosys Rise Insta Award (Jun 2022)

 Awarded for the involvement in Automation team and bringing new ideas to simplify the manual reporting task at program level.

Infosys Rise Insta Award (Jan 2022)

• Awarded for scaling up in ITSM process and for exhibiting skills in reports Automation and process standardization.



Personal Details

- Name Vishnu Ajith
- Date of Birth 07/05/1999
- Nationality Indian
- Marital Status Single
- Address Chullikkad (H), Calicut, Kerala
- LinkedIn Profile https://www.linkedin.com/in/vishnu-ajith-6206b91b1/
- GitHub Profile https://github.com/Vishnu2707



Declaration

• I hereby declare that all the information given above is true and correct to the best of my knowledge.